[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trosa automation
tutorial so this is our lesson 33 as an
overall tricentis Taska automation
Concepts and it is our lesson 18 in
terms of an advanced level
Concepts in this lesson you will learn
how can we perform multi language
testing by using trien tasar automation
tool and we are going to use regular
Expressions to handle the multi-
language testing by using trienes
Tas please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos thank
you so now let us jump onto the system
and see how can we automate test cases
related to multilanguage testing so this
is my trient Taska where I've created a
folder called multilingual testing and
then I've created one test case called
multilanguage test so let us first go to
website that we will be using to test
your multil language okay so if you see
this is my website mod.org and you can
see the content everything which is
showing in English right so now if I
change the language to
Dutch okay so if you see here accept the
titles see entire including the titles
everything is changed to Dutch see
everything is is Chang to Dutch language
right so now let us again go back to
English so now your entire content is in
English now I would like to automate one
test case of this
particular website by using tric Anda
okay let us go back to Tria and go to
modules I would like to scan this
particular some of the controls of you
this particular page right click and
then click on scan select
application so this will open your X
scan so what I'm doing I'm scanning all
the
controls when the website is showing in
English language okay keep that in mind
okay select the application click on
scan so now I'm going to
scan couple of
controls of this particular
page okay so just select select on
screen I would like to select this link
okay and then also I would like to
select the content of that particular
module that link content of that
particular link okay let's select this
content
so now if you see this content is not
uniquely
identified uh let me make it as
unique I made it as unique If You
observe
[Music]
closely this link has the property
called inner text and your tag and this
content let's make it
as I'm renaming this this as model
LMS description okay description so this
description has tag and inner text that
that
particular content basically the entire
text of text is it's inner text okay so
now let us rename
this as mod.org okay let me sorry let me
remove this select on screen now just
rename this to model OKAY model mod.org
so I just captured these two okay let's
save
this and close it okay so let us go back
to our
tonasa and let us see here okay so I
want to understand see this is what we
just now scan If You observe closely if
you see here model LMS this link has
inner text called mod LMS and your tag
and this description has inner text of
this entire text that is displaying here
right so let us create a test case now
okay just bring this module to the right
side and let's drag this module and drop
into your test case so what I going to
do so here before I run the test case
right I would like to change the
sequence of the controls I would like to
bring this description
first and then the link okay so that's
okay so now so this is description this
is link now I would like to verify if
this content exist on the page or not
okay so for that let's click
on here and click on your inner
text and I'm I'm going to specify not in
the text let's say I would like to say
exist equal to
true I'm
specifying Taska to
verify if that particular element exists
on the screen this particular
description exist on the screen in the
same way I look to validate if this
link exist then I would like to click on
that
link okay I would like to click on the
link first verify this and then click on
link okay so let me just simply run this
particular test case right click and
run first it ver verifies the content in
English and it clicks on
link so done so now it verified the
content and then it clicked on the link
okay so let us open your
Tria and see the results okay so if you
see the results here the verification is
successful and it clicked on your link
okay so now let us say I will change
this to Dutch I will change the language
to
Dutch so then this content it tries to
verify the content in English language
it won't find let's run this now let's
run this it's going to fail the test
case because the first content does not
exist it
fails see your test case is failed now
because the content has been changed
from English to Dutch so now how can we
handle this kind of scenarios how can I
automate the test
case so that the test cases will be
successful whatever the language you
select okay so let us for that let us
first go here I would like to use some
regular Expressions so let's bring this
module here okay we want to change the
properties of particular module okay
just simply bring
here and first let us first concentrate
on this description okay let's go here
this particular description has inner
text property so now instead of hard
coding this inner text property let's go
here and then put it into English
language
okay I would like to remove this one so
basically instead of this entire text
I'm just making it as regular expression
let's keep it okay so now I would like
to start using the regular expression
Reg
ex okay sorry curly braces Rec ex and
then open Square
Braes and here I'm going to specify the
text that I would like to see here what
is the inner text this is the inner text
right so here this is the inner text in
English
language that I would like to see and
then I need to use
R either if this particular element can
have this inner text at the end I
specified as that means whatever the
text it maybe okay first it should match
all this English language or it should
match your Dutch language let's go here
change it to Dutch so it should match
the Dutch language what is the language
is right click and then inspect here I
would like to take the inner text okay
for this Dutch language
so if you see here if you
expand if you expand the card this is
the language I would like to copy this
language and I would like to specify or
it can contain this I'll
say from here star okay and then close
your square brackets close your curly
braces so before I close this square
brackets I need to close your
columns open your curly braces reg x r g
x open your square
bracket right open your square bracket
let's bring it left side again okay so
what I'm doing
here I simply open curly braces rig X
open square
brackets colon your English language
inner text or it's a pipe symbol or your
Dutch language inner text and close
your colon close square brackets close
your curly braces so for inner text I
used regular expression at the end to
make sure that it won't fil okay so done
now save this now okay so if I run the
test case now the test case should pass
in Dutch language as well okay let's
right click and then run this
okay so your test case is now passed you
can see let's go back to our test result
and
see it actually matched
your content in Dutch also let us again
go back here let us change back to
English and see if it gets failed pass
sorry okay I want to again change it to
English and then simply run the test
case
again it should handle both the
languages English and Dutch so when I
run this particular test
case it validates the content in English
and your test case will be
passed yeah so if you see
here it successfully
validated whether the description exist
or not and then it clicked on your
link so if you have any queries leave
your queries in the comment box I'll try
to respond to your queries
hope you all understand the concept of
how can we automate
multilanguage test cases by using
tricentis tasa automation tool please do
subscribe to the channel click on Bell
icon you'll receive notifications
whenever I publish more videos thank
you